You wish you any travel meetings when it's back to those SUVA meetings.
Okay, we're going to call it over there.
You're a council meeting for today's day and time.
Item 2 is, except $5,000 donation from a travel council for
Constitution, for Splash, PAD, Fencing, and Chief Spartan Chief Cooker here.
Please come to the mic if you have some comments that you want to share.
Well, thank you, Mayor.
I just want to say that, excuse me, on behalf of the nine travel leaders of North East Oklahoma, the inner travel council,
we're pleased to be a part of your project.
A couple of months ago, Mrs. Hogan came out and appeared before the inner travel council,
presented the ambitious program about the Splash pad,
and, of course, as nine travel leaders, they knew nothing about it.
We asked Chief Cook to kind of work with the city and see what was taking place.
And at our last council meeting, it was unanimously approved by the nine travel leaders to present the city with a check for $5,000.
And Chief Cook and I are here today to do that.
And we're glad to be a part of this project.
And I also would like to, that I continually seeing the nine tribes,
entering into projects with the city, and as well as accounting other entities.
And we're very proud that we're able to do that.
And we want to work with you and our doors open, so feel free to come and visit where this any time.
And I'll ask Chief Cook to give someone the check for $5,000.
That is a lynching here.
Do we have to do it somewhere?
I don't know.
Chief Cook.
If you have a step right here, we'll get the lynching on the outside.
Chief Cook, you want to do it too?
I'll look at you there for a good picture.
If you can't, if you can, if you can, if you can, if you can, if you can.
I just want to echo your comments.
I mean, I know Chief Cook, you'll focus on that bridge immensely.
And it's been a great partnership.
And since I've been on the council, we really appreciate it.
We just want to keep it up.
Thank you.
I was just about to say that only.
Okay.
I'm three.
It is public hearing on the F-I-2017-2018 budget.
This public hearing is called for any member of the public to present to the governing body,
common for recommendations or information on any part of the proposed budget.
Is there anyone in the audience that wants to...
address the council or make any comments on the proposed budget.
Deena, are there any updates for the benefit of the public that's watching that?
Since we've last discussed, I'd like to talk about it.
I'd be happy to mention just one thing about the timing.
The budget itself, I believe, no change since the last time we met.
So, where it's exactly what we have been talking about.
The MDI.
If I could, that's what I was going to talk about, okay, okay, okay, it's good.
You might notice that this agenda normally would have had the approval of the actual budget on this meeting.
We've pushed that model until our meeting on June 20th.
The reason why, in part of our agenda tonight, we're going to be talking about the Civic Center modifications.
We're going to be opening the bids for the Civic Center modifications on the 15th of this month.
Normally, part of your budget approval would be a resolution, which would identify the amount of rainy day fun that the city would have.
The two items on the rainy day fun, the two resolutions that would have gone before you.
One is a $94,000 loan for the MDI, which is for the ballroom that you would ask us to do,
because currently we're paying about four or five percent interest on that.
If we owe it to ourselves, we can have a payout and say quite a bit of interest money.
The other is, as we had approved before, is roughly about a $2 million loan to ourselves
that would be coming from the rainy day fun that would pay for the Civic Center remodeling.
Instead of doing those two items tonight, because we're so close to actually opening the bids,
I wanted to go ahead and wait and have those approved on the 20th, because if we open the bids and they come in at $2 million, $100,000, for example.
Then we'd have to scramble to try to find that $100,000, whereas if we added that into the resolution,
you would have that resolution to be able to approve and it would track with the program.
Now, obviously if the bids come in way too high, we're back to the drawing board.
But I know that Jill and Lindsay and Kevin have been working so hard with our contractor,
and that our contractor is going to be here tonight to talk about a couple other items.
We feel very confident that this is going to be within that $2 million range.
So we just wanted to have that accuracy.
So for that reason, we pushed off approving both the budget and those resolutions regarding the rainy day fun.
So we would have more of an accurate number.
We're still well within the state regulations and relationship to adopting the budget if we approve it on the 20th.
Okay.
So we're still in the public hearing portion.
I'm just going to ask once more, is there anyone in the audience that wishes to address the council,
or ask any questions about the budget as proposed at this time?
We're not going to close the public hearing on the F5 2017-2018 budget, as Dean said,
they actually voted in approval of the budget with any minor changes that may occur.
We'll happen at our meeting on the 20th.
Item four is public input, non-schederal personal appearances.
If there's anyone in the audience, it wishes to address the council on any of the other
council agenda items.
And there, nobody beating a trail to the mic, we're going to move on to item five, which is
a consent agenda.
Staff is recommending items six through 16 for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items, I'd entertain a motion.
I'll just do it right there.
And second.
Second.
Go a call, please.
No consent.
Less than so.
Five.
Item seven, two, which I wanted you to a moment ago, discussion of the revised council
and slash totally designed.
I'll please two.
Okay.
Did you do anything?
I don't think I know.
I'll click it back on that.
I can't just go ahead and explain what we're doing tonight.
We have staff have been working on the arrangements in this building once the renovation takes
place.
But in working with our architect, what we recognize is that the arrangement for what has been
proposed is both the council chambers and the courtroom, where the finance is right by the
main entrance, the arrangement is going to be a little different.
And we talk about our preferences in doing it and we recognize the fact that of all the things,
this is going to be the most public item, it's going to be the one that affects the council
most.
So what we wanted to do was before we really get into this, we want to make sure we're on the
right track with you.
And be sure that everybody understands what this design would do.
There's a lot of benefits too, so I think we're all pretty happy with what we're presenting,
but it is different from the way we're sitting seated right now and just wanted to go through
that with you tonight.
So Jill, if I can turn it over to you.
So the bottom drawing is the existing one and it's 24 feet, 26 inches wide by 39 feet
to inches.
So in total, this entire window is going to be filled by 39.
The proposed room, I'm not going to sit, when we've got them sitting exactly how they'd be
sitting.
So right now you're facing west.
The new proposal have you facing north.
The new room will be 38 feet, 7 inches wide by 28, 8, and that's a difference of about
13 feet.
Almost 14 feet.
13, 11 feet difference.
So it's going to be much wider than how ever we'll have a...
So seven foot aisle right here, that's for the door, and you have to have a 48 inch turn around space minimum for ADA.
So if you took the seven feet off of that, that's really just a seven foot wider.
The difference with your day is quite a bit different. You can see that this is it's arched pretty good right now.
It's about 165 in width. The new one doesn't have quite the arch. It just has a small curve, but it's 22 feet, 3 inches long.
We did talk to Jeff Chesnet and our court administrator Carrie Taylor.
The judge would be sitting here, Carrie would be sitting here, the court clerk, and then a witness if there was such a, we had a witness stand.
They would be sitting there. He's very happy with that. They're both happy with that.
Talk about the elevation though, because that's very important for the judge.
I think it's 14 inches. Yeah. So he'll be 14 inches right now. He's like, 3, 4, 4, 2, 1 inches.
Okay. So he said, oh, let's see. I thought it was much worse, but so he was happy with that.
He still needed to be elevated, but he wasn't as much as he is now, but he wasn't. He was okay with that.
I actually talked to him Monday for the final disconnection to check that off.
You still have a same number of seating. You still have nine. You have nine right now, so it's still have nine.
I want to point out there's two TVs proposed. One would probably be facing, you know, tilted like this, facing you and one would be facing the crown.
Right now, it's proposing. We have 48 seats in here as we sit right now.
This is proposed 48 seats, but we can rearrange that however we want. We can have up to 60 seats.
That's without any tables, but I think we're going to definitely like the tables, because we can work learning the meetings.
That really does help. So we may want ask the, bring those back in.
But if we have a meeting that comes up that we know there's going to be a lot of people. We can add more seats and still being the right.
60 is the, is the, is the.
Yes.
That's the max for fire.
That's why we're talking about that from John today.
And then of course anything that's much larger will, we'll have the ball right.
Yes.
A couple of other things is the doors. There's three doors right now. There's two that are in the hallway right now.
The two existing doors now going into offices would stay.
I'm going to call those, you'd have to have a key code to get in, but anybody can get out at a crash bar to get out if there's a fire or something.
So, but to get in, you'd have to have a code.
The public door is up here to get in, and that will, that will be kind of loft as much as the councilwoman is locked just when no one's using it.
Or you're going to have to have stairs in that middle door, because if that's raised.
Yep. Yeah.
How do I be a, I have that John.
I know we have an ADA ramp right here.
And an ADA ramp there.
We have a six inch step up here.
John, you might introduce yourself.
I'm John, you'll introduce your two architects.
I have to make the two steps up here, to the judge's pitch, and we have one step up here to the county.
So, so that, we're not a better one, I'm going to call it a four step, but the steps are inside.
Yes, that's what I'm supposed to level here.
Okay.
And that's one step up here, and two there.
And also, you'll notice to the right, there's a handicap, right?
So if we have a person that sits in the diet, that has a disability, they'll be able to access two.
So it meets that ADA requirement.
It has the podium gone away.
No, what we have now, and it's not shown on here because there's no darkness.
We have three locations where we're going to have a full amount of electrical loss.
The podium can be brought out, but it may be one of the different places to come to the best state for whatever you guys needed to be.
Okay.
I happen to be talking to Chuck.
And he said, you, Joe had talked to him, and there were he had a couple of minor things that he asked for changes on,
but he said he was pretty excited about it overall.
Yeah.
We kind of went back and forth on the court clerk in the witness stand where who was going to sit where in the face.
So we were able to accommodate those changes.
He didn't tell me what they were.
He just mentioned it.
Y'all had talked about it a couple of thoughts.
Where do you bring the prisoners in?
Well, I don't do that anymore.
They do it electronically with tonight.
Okay.
It's kind of a sky thing.
Yes.
And he loves it.
It's worked out for months now.
They love it.
Has it just been recently?
They went to the air.
This is the air.
Yeah.
It's a current month.
No, I haven't been in there in six months.
Good.
Keep it that way.
But the nice thing about that sky is not only, is it much more convenient, but you don't have a cost or the risk of prison transfer.
It's great idea.
Because we had a whole different discussion about a year ago about that very thing.
It's been about four months later.
They started that.
So it worked out beautifully.
It's a good idea.
Something too.
So I'm going to start talking about the rehab itself.
We're planning on moving Kevin Browning's.
Yeah.
He said this will break into three pieces.
And he thinks we can get it out there.
And the court and counsel, the rooms, or meetings, will happen in the dining room.
It'll be in the southwest corner just right over here.
And we plan on moving this right after this next meeting on the 20th on the 21st.
We'll be moving in that.
So the 20th will be the last meeting in this.
Where is the council?
Two.
What's that?
Space train where the council sets and how big of a space is that right there?
Where?
From the end of the council setting to the to the wall.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm about six or eight feet.
Jill and the rare instance of a jury trial, which I think I did the last one that was held in city court about 30 years ago
With the jury be sitting at the council seating is that what's contemplating?
Well, and I'm thinking what's contemplated is we'd set up some kind of a box right here or the seating right here, but they could sit here
The nine is enough.
You only need six.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm sitting there.
And our prosecutor will probably sit right here and then will probably, if the tables are in there, one of the tables will serve as the defendant's table desk.
Questions?
Now I'll talk to her if you haven't got the detector.
Have to get a visual.
Okay.
And that's what they all got all the minutes first and then find out what is it?
Time, time, time, frame.
Now obviously the resolution of the 20th will have the amount.
Even by then we're not sure if we open the beds, we've got to make sure that they meet all specifications.
We might not have that for you by the 20th, but at least we'll know the amount of the fifth.
And we can start planning accordingly.
Also I think one important thing to remember is there are going to be windows that the council will be facing.
But of course we're going to have screens and things such as that.
So you know they can be closed during sunny days or open hours or the council decides.
Well we have a better idea.
What modifications and renovations are going to be done based on the bed amounts.
We're looking at paint and carpet and that type of thing.
Yes.
Planning, electrical, h-back, roof.
Okay.
That's going to talk about.
And that's why that's what we held off is that if there's any kind of a small deviation.
We don't want to get the point where we're worried about carpet or we'd like to be able to make sure that you're approving the amount.
We're just looking at the design now that's.
Yeah.
And this is just for the court and the council.
But we're going to be any new security features or procedures or anything.
I know we plan on putting if you've seen some of our doors, we have a lot of code entry doors now and that's going to continue.
And in reality this this setup is much better for security in the two doors with the bars behind the people to do exit case of that.
And we're moving all the public interaction to a one area.
That's to me right now.
We have people in this building that we don't know.
If we had a fire or something, we wouldn't know who's in this building, sometimes because
the walkers and the just different things going on.
So it'll be a lot safer.
The large amount of the project and the cost of the project is going to be the roofing, the
heating and air systems.
I mean, that's going to be the monster amount of that not the type of thing we're talking
about.
But obviously, we're talking about it's going to be the most noticeable for somebody that
is going to be the most noticeable thing.
And I think one thing that we talked about a long time ago, the plans currently are that
the gymnasium will have an air system.
So we talked about making sure that it's not just for the employees, but also for the public
that uses the building that we're making it much more friendly.
Yeah, the questions?
Okay.
There's a lot more room in there and what do you think?
I'm so long, my chair will still fit.
I'm going to have these chairs for a buy-in.
I'm making authorizing the manager to accept the notion of a lot, 338 Bell Monavition, 2020 and
on these most one actors, 2020 and on these, even more west from West Fargo.
Yeah.
Well, West Fargo has a program that they approached us with about a month ago, where they'll
take property that's of a certain value and contact non-profits or the municipality in
a town.
And see if they're interested in taking on the property to do something with.
And you've got a certain timeframe within, you've got to rehab the property or demo the property
or get it into somebody else's hands for them to do that with.
And this is part of their urban renewal basically program that they have.
And this address, 2020-9, E-North West, is a property that they identified as one that they
would like to see the city take offered it to the city along with a $5,000 cellar concession.
And that money would come to the city if we accepted the donation and we could do what
we wanted to then with the property.
So, Chris, you have not heard of that.
They're asking us for $5,000 and the living is the property on the property on the property.
So, this is part of that.
So, this is part of the property on the property on the property on the property on the property.
We had gone and looked at the property at 2029, E-North West and I think in your packet
there were pictures that you were able to see on the outside the property looked like it might
be one that we could use and try to get into somebody's hands for this.
to do something weird. But then when myself and Travis went over to look at the inside of the
property with the ruler, it became obvious that that's probably not what we would want to do
with this particular property. We still hope to do that at some point with another program and
another piece of property, but on this one it didn't feel like once we went through it that it was
a viable candidate to be rehabbed or to rehab it would have to be completely gutted and redone.
How many lots is this end? This is actually, this is a smaller lot, so it's one lot that we're looking at
and it is forty by one twenty and it's on a corner there at twenty twenty nine. So since it is a corner
lot with an alley back behind it, there's different setbacks for it between the side and the front
and the back and set back. So it doesn't limit itself very well to have another house. This house right here,
I believe is just a little bit over seven hundred square feet. Yeah, very small. So it doesn't limit itself
to have another house to be built on it very easily. So what I've done is I'm concentrating another evening
a second house. No, a new house. Tarr it down and build back. It doesn't, the size of a lot with the setbacks,
we have in place now and it being on a corner doesn't make it a viable property on its own to build
a new house on it. I'm maintaining that property now. I'm mowing in Wells Fargo is. Wells Fargo is.
Yeah, well actually, I believe it's Susan Rhodes is who their agent here is here in town. So
but what I've done is I've gone to the gentleman who lives next door at twenty twenty five and spoke to him,
he has the same size lot and basically the same size house on that lot and talked to him about
would it be open to at some point once the city got control of the property, beating the property to
him to make it one larger lot, then it would be 80. His lot is 40 by 120 also. So it would be 80 by 120
and make it a viable lot at some point to build one house on both both lots in exchange for that.
I mean he would be responsible for paying the taxes and mowing and everything to do with the, to do
with the lot. What do you think is going to cost a demo of that crystal? Well we're working on our
demo contractor right now so I can't give you a definite cost but my estimate is a-
around 3,000. So the 5,000 were more than covered. Yes, the down cost. Can we actually give
that land, okay? We could, we would work that out. Yes, okay. Questions? So you're all
the rest in 4,000 tonight is authorization to accept the proper. Right, that I would have
to come back once we had the property and was further down the road and to do something
with it. But the intent is not for the city to keep the property and have to know it and
maintain it. The intent would be to do something with it that would make it viable for citizen
years. Okay. Any questions, concerns? No. Okay. So do we have a motion to approve acceptance
of the donation? Most of your improvement. Second, second. Low call, please. Johnson,
Western, short. All right. Thanks, Christine. Any other new business? Staff reports on your packet. Any
new, you said you had an announcement out in 21? Yeah, we did. You know, I've went along in our grand
trials. You had to kind of left-print this off for tonight. I'm going to read it all. But the
same thing program for the residents of Miami, the build line is June 22nd. You can go to a website,
a mile note, the dot net, under emergency management. You can get the phone there and tell y'all
us over there, I guess. But again, the deadline is June 22nd. It's a great program. If you can
make a great program, I hope anyone that's watching it is in need of the save room will definitely
apply. I'm sure there's stipulations you have to on the library, it's center. But certainly a worthwhile
program, or fortunate that funding was made available again. By the state management, will that
require permanent Travis to install those? Yes. Okay.
Senator Manjor, do you have any questions, Dave? I just had one. I have passed along to everybody.
I report that Christie had written about the progress on the demolition of the Eagle picture building.
And I know the contractors out there today are working. I think the only thing that we discovered
that we expected to discover is once the building was taken down, there's a lot more chat. And
no DQ is going to be going through a change order to be able to immediately chat. It's on the
property. But we've been very happy with the way things have been going out of the fall of
side for putting the demolition remnants out there and trying to get that site closed off for chief
fall.
as well because he was good enough to let us use that land as a landfill site for several
years now. So everything seems to be going very well. We've got everything mapped out
and then I think once probably in the very not-to-distant future we're going to be starting
to work on the actual plans and designs for the splash pad itself. So it's moving along but
I just wanted to compliment Chris because that if you drive by there you can see what a major
project is to take a building down that size and a lot of a lot of moving parts and so far it's
so good. Well I'm fast to actually the progress and the wonderful thing that people are watching
or wondering about it, it's nice to kind of go behind your facility, go to the parking lot of the
ball field and look and you can start seeing how that has opened up that entire area of town. It's really
really beautified the place already. It has it looks good yeah. And I saw a note also on the
tire cleanup to success of that of over 700 tires. If I had one of our tire companies and this was
completely well one of our tire companies on Steve O was brought in about 400. So we have 400 fewer tires
on Steve O's Boulevard. So that's a good idea. Good. Are they pulling out of business? I don't believe so
but I think that they recognize that this is a great opportunity to get rid of some of their old
stock at taxpayers' diamond. That's what that, that's what that project is for. That's it.
That's it. Okay. I'm 23. It was exactly a session for soon that 25 O S 3071 for the purpose of
discussing employment to it being screwed off in beach and Chuck Chessner and also 25 O S 307 before
for confidential communications with the City Attorney concerning a pending investigation or claim
to it during Anderson versus City of Miami in the Board of Review and City of Miami at all versus
G-RDA and ASBELL. So we're going to do we have a mostly go into executive session for the reasons
listed under agenda item 23. I'm going to pray and for the record. Go ahead please. Be my recommendation
that we need to go into the executive session for the discussion of the litigation issues
because those are matters that cannot be discussed openly in public. Okay. So I'll make a motion for
the reasons you started there. Okay. And it's the end-bands. Handbands. We're all colleagues. Johnson.
Western. I'll show it.